Gabriel Costa Gonçalves

gcgoncalves88@gmail.com 087 605 1353 http://gcgoncalves.github.io http://linkedin.com/in/gcgoncalves

B.Sc. in Computer Science from Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul, elected the best Computer Science College in Brazil. Programming language agnostic, I have five years of experience developing on both back and front-end of websites and web-based applications in environments ranging from startups to international companies.

Professional Experience:

Cloud Developter at IBM

December/2018 – Present

Working under IBM WCE team,
provisioning a and maintaining IKS
clusters.

Web Developter at IBM

June/2017 – December/2018

Working under IBM mySA team,
developing a SaaS CRM platorm.

Software Engineer at Azion Technologies (CDN) May/2016 – May 2017

Cloud platform for content delivery and acceleration with global operations and more than 25 points of presence around the globe.

Software Engineer at Superplayer (Startup)

September/2015 – April/2016 Music streaming service with more than a million active users on the web, android and iOS.

Intern at Pmweb (Digital Marketing Agency)

March/2014 – August/2015 Multiple times award winner digital marketing agency focused on the hospitality business.

- Development and maintenance of ansible playbooks for infrastructure management and monitoring.
- Deploy and maintain IKS clusters.
- Develop a web dashboard for cluster management.
- · Unit Testing.
- Development and maintenance of a CRM used by IBM business partners.
- Responsible for the full stack (server-side application logic and front-end development).
- Unit Testing and E2E Testing.
- Development and maintenance of components on the Azion CDN configuration software.
- Lead front end developer.
- Responsible for the full stack (server-side application logic and front-end development).
- Test Driven Development and Domain Driven Development.
- Development and maintenance of components on the superplayer music player platform.
- Responsible for the full stack (server-side application logic and front-end development).
- Data and results analysis.
- A/B Testing.
- Development and maintenance of websites for hotels and resorts.
- Responsible for the full stack (server-side application logic and front-end development).
- Email marketing development.
- Database management.

Intern at Sthima (Startup)
April/2013 – February/2014
B2B web base CRM software developme

B2B web base CRM software development company targeting medium-sized enterprises.

- Development and maintenance of cloud-based CRM software.
- Responsible for the full stack (server-side application logic and front-end development).
- Minor CSS and JavaScript adjustments.
- Database management.

Education:

B.Sc. in Computer Science Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul 2008 – 2015

Courses:

User Experience Design ESPM 2017 - 16 hours

Design Intro Valkiria IC 2014 - 16 hours

Skills:

- Excellent programming logics.
- Front-end: HTML, JavaScript, CSS/Sass and frameworks such as AngularJs, ReactJs and Bootstrap.
- Back-end: Python, JavaScript (Node.js), C#/ASP.NET and PHP.
- Good understanding of RESTful services.
- Experience in SQL and NoSQL modeling and querying.
- Version control tools experience using Git and SVN.
- UX Design enthusiast.